Kainan Doneson

Woodstock, NY, 12498| 805-284-3987 | kaindoneson@gmail.com

Github: kainan54 | Medium | LinkedIn

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experienced in Ruby and JavaScript-based programming. Created projects with React and Rails frameworks. With a background in retail and service industries, I have strong teamwork skills from working with diverse groups of individuals. A passionate learner who is excited to help innovative companies solve problems, and achieve goals.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages/Libraries/Frameworks: Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML, CSS, TypeScript

Other: Github, DOM, JSON, Effective Communication, Team Oriented

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

ARt App - | Github | Video Demo

ARt App is a web app that enables users to share images and view them in 3D and AR. Users can also interact through likes, comments, and followers.

- Used React/ JS for frontend and Rails API/Ruby for backend
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and Bcrypt Gem for user authorization from front to backend
- Applied Three.Js Library to make a 3D viewer that users could apply to uploaded images
- Incorporated ARJS to make a view layer where users can view uploaded images with a hiro marker/camera
- Leveraged Rails Active Storage(in dev mode) to enable user photo uploads

GeoTunes - Github | Video Demo

Geotunes is a web application designed to allow users to create and share custom google map routes with Spotify playlists attached to them.

- Used React/ JS for frontend and Rails API/Ruby for backend
- Integrated GoogleMaps to enable users to make custom routes on a shared map
- Applied Spotify React Components to enable users to attach public playlists to custom routes
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and Bcrypt Gem for user authorization from front to backend

Flappy Demon- Github | Video Demo

Loot based web video game. Players are able to collect items/power-ups by defeating enemies or by purchasing them from the item shop. Users are ranked based on the amount of currency gained from selling items.

- Used Phaser3/Vanilla-JS for frontend and Rails API/Ruby for backend
- Meshed dom elements to respond to Phaser3 game logic
- Utilized Rails API to persist player items and rankings

EXPERIENCE

Lounge 247 Manhattan NY 02/2019 - 03/2020 Barback/tender

- Interacted with customers and prepared beverages for high-volume bar patrons
- Check customers' identification to ensure compliance with all beverage regulations
- Maintained bar and storage areas and restocked bar inventory and supplies

Apple WTC Manhattan, NY

Back of House Specialist

Retail Specialist

11/2018 - 01/2019

- Worked alongside team members rotating different BOH tasks to keep things running smoothly
- Receiving product shipments and orderly storing them for easy retrieval later on
- Document, label, and ship out product returns/repairs to the main depot

Interacted with customers to target technical needs and suggest product solutions

01/2018 - 11/2018

- Advised customers and provided guidance and explanations on setting up their new technology
- Maintained visual merchandising and stayed updated on new products and initiatives

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Brooklyn, NY 08/2020 - 11/2020